<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE legalnotice PUBLIC 
  "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">

<legalnotice>
 <title>Legal Notices</title>
 <para>Novell, Inc. makes no representations or warranties with respect to the
contents of us eof this documentataion, and specifially disclaims any express
or implied warranties of merchantability or fitness for any particular purpose.
Further, Novell, Inc. reserves the right to revise this publication and to make
changes to its content, at any time, without obligation to notify any person or
entity of such revisions or changes.</para>
 <para>Further, Novell, Inc. makes no representations or warranties with
respect to any software, and specifically disclaims any express or implied
warranties of merchantability or fitness for any particular purpose. Further,
Novell, Inc. reserves the right to make changes to any and all parts of Novell
software, at any time, without any obligations to notify any person or entity
of such changes.</para>
 <para>You may not use, export, or re-export this product in violation of any
applicable laws or regulations including, without limitation, U.S. export
regulations or the laws of the country in which you reside.</para>
 <para>Copyright &copy;&nbsp;<?dbtimestamp format="Y"?> Novell Inc. All rights
reserved. No part of this publication may be reproduced, photocopied, stored on
a retrieval system, or transmitted without the express written consent of the
publisher.</para>
 <para>Novell Inc. has intellectual property rights relating to technology
embodied in the product that is described in this document. In particular, and
without limitation, these intellectual property rights may include one or more
of the U.S. patents listed at <ulink
url="http://www.novell.com/company/legal/patents/"/> and on or more additional
patents or pending applications in the U.S. and in other countries.</para>
 <literallayout>

Novell, Inc.
404 Wyman Street, Suite 500
Waltham, MA 02451
U.S.A.

www.novell.com

</literallayout>

 <formalpara>
  <title>Online Documentation</title>
  <para>To access the online documentation for this and other Novell Products,
and to get update, see <ulink url="http://www.novell.com/documentation"/>.</para>
 </formalpara>
</legalnotice>


<!-- Keep this comment at the end of the file
Local variables:
mode: xml
sgml-indent-step: 1
coding: utf-8
End:
-->

