<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet
 href="urn:x-daps:xslt:profiling:docbook45-profile.xsl" 
 type="text/xml"
 title="Profiling step"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "entity-decl.ent">
%entities;
]>
<chapter id="cha.daps.user.review">
 <title>Review and Translation Processes</title>
 <para>
  <remark>output with remarks/draft/meta-data, tarballs, bigfile, locdrop</remark>
 </para>
  <abstract>
  <para>This chapter describes:
  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem><para>&wip;</para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
  </para>
 </abstract>
 <sect1 id="sec.daps.user.review.output.">
   <title>Output with Remarks, Metadata or Draft Watermark</title>
   <para>
      &dapsacr; offers a number of features to simplify review and
      translation processes. For example, you can insert
      <sgmltag>remark</sgmltag> elements in the source code and generate an
      output format that either includes or suppresses these remarks. You
      can also generate preview versions of your documentation with a
      <literal>DRAFT</literal> watermark appearing on the HTML or PDF
      output. If you use &dm; in addition to &dapsacr;, you can
      <quote>flag</quote> your XML files with meta-information (like
      workflow status). &dapsacr; offers an option to also display this
      meta-information in the generated output. <!--For handing over your files
      to review or translation, &dapsacr; can create tarballs of the XML
      sources and graphics.--></para>
      
   <para>
     For publishing a pre-release version of a document that you might want
     to send to a proofreader for review, &dapsacr; provides several features, 
     like enabling <literal>DRAFT</literal> watermark, including file metadata in
     the output (like file maintainer or editing statusa use the <option>--draft</option>
     command option to mark the document as draft version. For example, use
     the following command to build a color PDF that has a
     <literal>DRAFT</literal> watermark printed on each page:
    </para>
   <screen>$ <command>daps -d &dc;-daps-example color-pdf --draft</command></screen>
   <para>
     If you used <sgmltag>remark</sgmltag> elements in your XML files (for
     editorial remarks or questions to the proofreader), include the remarks
     in the output with the <option>--remarks</option> option:
    </para>
   <screen>$ <command>daps -d &dc;-daps-example color-pdf --remarks</command></screen>
   <para>When generating PDFs with FOP, the contents of the remark elements 
     is shown in italics within the text. XEP supports conversion of remark 
     elements into PDF annotations. This feature is enabled in &dapsacr; by
     default, but if you want XEP to treat remark elements like FOP does, you
     can change the respective &dapsacr; parameter.<remark>taroth 2012-10-16:
     todo - add link as soon as this is covered in &dapsuser;</remark>
     Enabling remarks automatically turns draft mode on.
    </para>
   <note>
    <title>Output with Remarks or Draft Watermark</title>
    <para>
      The command options <option>--draft</option> option and
      <option>--remarks</option> are supported for HTML and PDF, but not for
      all &dapsacr; output formats.
     </para>
   </note>
   <para>
     By default, &dapsacr; adds a string to the base name of the output file
     to flag output formats generated with special options. Example file
     names are <filename>daps-example_draft_en.pdf</filename> or
     <filename>daps-example_remarks_draft_en.pdf</filename>.
    </para>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
