<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="urn:x-daps:xslt:profiling:docbook45-profile.xsl" 
 type="text/xml"
 title="Profiling step"?>
<!DOCTYPE glossary PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"[
  <!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "entity-decl.ent">
  %entities;
]>
<glossary id="daps.glossary">
 <title>Glossary</title>
  <remark>toms 2013-01-18: Add XIncludes to glossary</remark>
 <glossentry id="glos.antennahouse"><glossterm>Antenna House Formatter</glossterm>
  <glosssee otherterm="glos.formatter"/></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.condtext"><glossterm>Conditional Text</glossterm>
  <glosssee otherterm="glos.profiling"/></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.dtd"><glossterm id="term.dtd">Document Type Definition</glossterm><acronym id="acr.dtd"
   >DTD</acronym>
  <glossdef>
   <para> The DTD (Document Type Definition) defines the exact elements, entities attributes and
    structure available in a XML or HTML document. </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.doctype"><glossterm>DOCTYPE</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para> The DOCTYPE, or Document Type <emphasis>Declaration</emphasis>, not to be confused with a
     <xref endterm="term.dtd" linkend="glos.dtd"/>, contains the information on the <xref endterm="acr.dtd"
     linkend="glos.dtd"/> to use with an XML document. Therefore, it also defines which particular
    XML format is for the document. </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.daps"><glossterm>DocBook Authoring and Publishing
   Suite</glossterm><acronym>DAPS</acronym>
  <glossdef>
   <para> DAPS provides authors of technical documentation with an easy-to-use toolchain to convert
    their DocBook documents into various output formats. </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>  
 <glossentry id="glos.docbook"><glossterm>DocBook</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para>DocBook is a semantic markup language for technical documentation published as a DTD.
   </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.entity"><glossterm>Entity</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para>
    An entity connects one or multiple characters with a unique identifier. One
    example where this is used, is for escaping characters that are necessary for
    XML markup. A character such as <literal>&amp;</literal> must be
    written as the entity <code>&amp;amp;</code> in XML.
    <remark>FIXME? Does this sound okay? sknorr, 30-08-2012</remark>
   </para>
   <para>
    You can also declare custom entities.
   </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.formatter"><glossterm>FO Formatter</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para>Renders the XSL-FO files which are created by the DocBook XSL stylesheets
    into various output formats. The output format used most often is likely PDF.
    Formats that can usually be rendered into include:</para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
     <para> Page description formats such as PDF, Postscript, and XPS. </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para> Different raster and vector image formats such as PNG and SVG. </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para> Text documents and Web page documents such as TXT, RTF, and HTML. </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para> Internal formats of the formatter. </para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   <para>Well-known formatters include Apache FOP, XEP, and Antenna House Formatter. Whereas the
    former is an open-source product, the latter two are proprietary solutions. Antenna
    House Formatter is incompatible with &dapsacr;.</para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.fo"><glossterm>Formatting Objects</glossterm><acronym>FO</acronym>
  <glosssee otherterm="glos.xslfo"/>
 </glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.FOP"><glossterm>Formatting Objects Processor</glossterm><acronym>FOP</acronym>
  <glosssee otherterm="glos.formatter"/></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.mainelement"><glossterm id="term.deliverable">Main Element</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para>
    Within this guide, main element refers to any XML element that is commonly 
    used to create a coherent whole in an output format. In other words, either 
    a <sgmltag>book</sgmltag>, an <sgmltag>article</sgmltag>, or a 
    <sgmltag>set</sgmltag>.
   </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.pdf"><glossterm>Portable Document Format</glossterm><acronym>PDF</acronym>
  <glossdef>
   <para>
    PDF is a page description format created by Adobe Systems in 1993. Today, it
    is widely adopted as the standard format for digitally distributed
    page-oriented documents. A major advantage of PDF is the possibility to view
    it in exactly the same form on different platforms.
   </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.pi"><glossterm>Processing Instruction</glossterm><acronym>PI</acronym>
  <glossdef>
   <para>
    PIs can be used to mark certain content as having to be treated differently
    by writing an instruction enclosed in <code>&lt;?</code> and <code>?&gt;</code>.
    This is commonly used within (X)HTML web pages to mark parts of the file as
    being written in server-side scripting language PHP.
   </para>
   <para>In DocBook, Processing Instructions can also be used for somewhat more
   mundane purposes, such as setting the background color of a preceding image.
   </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.profiling"><glossterm>Profiling</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para> Through profiling, you can easily adapt your documentation to different variants of a
    product. For instance, a manufacturer of white-label products might appreciate being able to
    easily replace the brand name for the product they sell.</para>
   <para>
    It is possible to further this concept and even replace entire sections
    of text depending on a product's target group, for instance, on whether
    documentation is generated for the entry-level or for the professional
    version of a product.
   </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.project"><glossterm>Project</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para>
    A project consist of all the files that lie in a directory structure as 
    required by &dapsacr;, with the first directory level containing any &dc;
    files and subdirectories for <filename>xml</filename> files and
    <filename>images</filename>. When the first
    <xref linkend="glos.mainelement"/> is built, an additional
    subdirectory called <filename>build</filename> will be created.
   </para>
   <para>
    Such a <emphasis>project directory</emphasis> may contain the source files
    for multiple main elements.
   </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.svg"><glossterm>Scalable Vector Graphics</glossterm><acronym>SVG</acronym>
  <glossdef>
   <para> SVG is an XML-based vector graphics format, which is supported by most modern Web browsers. </para>
   <para> Vector graphics formats are different from traditional raster graphics in that they
    describe the exact shape of an object instead of using the lossy process of subdividing an
    object into many individual raster points (such as pixels). </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.stylesheet"><glossterm>Stylesheet</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para>In the context of DocBook, the term <emphasis>stylesheet</emphasis>
    usually refers to the <xref linkend="glos.xslt"/> stylesheets used to
    transform DocBook documents into their respective output formats.</para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.transformation"><glossterm>Transformation</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para> Data transformation converts data from a source data format into a destination data
    format. An example is the process of converting a DocBook XML document into HTML by using an
    XSLT processor. </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.validation"><glossterm>Validation</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para> Validation refers to the process of checking whether an XML document is formally correct,
    checking, for instance, if all XML tags are properly closed and nested. This is done using a DTD
    or XML Schema. </para>
   <para><remark>Sound good? sknorr, 30-08-2012</remark>If a document is valid that does not mean that its contents are factually correct or that
    it is structured as you intended. However, validity does mean that a document can be further
    processed, for instance by a Web browser, or an XSL processor. </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.xep"><glossterm>XEP</glossterm>
  <glosssee otherterm="glos.formatter"/></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.xinclude"><glossterm>XInclude</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para>
    XIncludes are references to other DocBook files. XIncludes can be used to split one large file
    into multiple smaller, more manageable files. For instance, instead of having an entire book in
    a single file, you can create one central file from which you can reference individual chapter
    files. </para>
   <para> In the context of using a version control system within your documentation process, having smaller
    files can also help avoid version conflicts if you and co-workers are working on different
    chapters of the same book. </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.xmlcatalog"><glossterm>XML Catalog</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para>
    XML Catalogs can be used to make DTDs available locally, so they do not have
    to be downloaded over the network every time they are accessed.
   </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.xmlparser"><glossterm>XML Parser</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para>
    Also known as an <emphasis>XML Processor</emphasis>, an <emphasis>XML Parser</emphasis>
    is used to provide the structural information contained in an XML file to
    another application.
   </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry>
  <glossterm>XOP</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para> XOP (XML-binary Optimized Packaging) is a W3C (World Wide Web Consortium) recommendation
    on how to represent binary data inside XML documents. </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.xml"><glossterm>Extensible Markup Language</glossterm><acronym>XML</acronym>
  <glossdef>
   <para> XML is a markup language with rules to encode documents into a form that is both
    human-readable and machine-readable. </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.xsl"><glossterm>Extensible Stylesheet
   Language</glossterm><acronym>XSL</acronym>
  <glossdef>
   <para>
    XSL is a collective noun used to refer to <xref linkend="glos.xslt" endterm="acr.xslt" />,
    <xref linkend="glos.xslfo"/>, and the XML Path Language
    (XPath).
   </para>
   <glossseealso otherterm="glos.xslt"/>
   <glossseealso otherterm="glos.xslfo"/>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.xslfo"><glossterm>XSL-FO</glossterm>
  <glossdef>
   <para>FO, XSL-FO or <emphasis>Extensible Stylesheet Language-Formatting Objects</emphasis> is a
    markup language used to mediate between other XML representations and a page formatting format
    such as PDF. </para>
   <glossseealso otherterm="glos.xslt"/>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
 <glossentry id="glos.xslt"><glossterm>Extensible Stylesheet Language for
   Transformations</glossterm><acronym id="acr.xslt">XSLT</acronym>
  <glossdef>
   <para> XSLT or <emphasis>Extensible Stylesheet Language for Transformations</emphasis> is a
    language based on XML. It is used to transform XML documents. </para>
  </glossdef></glossentry>
</glossary>
