<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet
 href="urn:x-daps:xslt:profiling:docbook45-profile.xsl" 
 type="text/xml"
 title="Profiling step"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"
[<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "entity-decl.ent">
%entities;
]>
<chapter id="cha.daps.user.img">
 <title>Image Handling</title>
 <para>
  <remark>taroth 2012-03-14: todo: also add advanced feature like listings
  with daps etc.</remark>
 </para>
 <para>
  Depending on the output format you generate with &dapsacr; (PDF or HTML
  for example), the source images you provide and reference in your XML
  sources are automatically transformed into the appropriate output formats.
  For example, SVG images are converted to PNG for HTML builds, or color
  images to grayscale for black-and-white PDFs. For basic information about
  image handling (such as supported formats, where to store the images in
  your documentation directory, and how to reference them in your XML
  files), refer to <xref linkend="sec.daps.quick.imgs"/>.
 </para>
 <sect1 id="sec.daps.user.imgs.types">
  <title>Supported Image Types</title>
  &daps-img-formats;
 </sect1>
 <sect1 id="sec.daps.user.imgs.usage"> <!--Make this a sect2?-->
  <title>Where to Use Which Image Type</title>
  <sect2 id="sec.daps.user.imgs.usage.dia">
   <title><literal>DIA</literal></title>
   <para>
    The software Dia is a diagram editor which can be used to draw
    entity-relationship diagrams, UML diagrams, and flowcharts. It stores these
    diagrams in a custom XML-based vector format called <literal>DIA</literal>.
   </para>
   <para>
    Being a vector format, the <literal>DIA</literal> format is
    resolution-independent, meaning that an image made in it can be displayed or
    printed as large or small as you wish without artifacts.
   </para>
   <para>
    Dia makes it very easy to connect elements, to add text and to use simple
    fill and border colors. Although it can import <literal>SVG</literal> files as
    shapes, it is not useful for drawing shapes freely itself. It also make it
    relatively hard to create complex or effect-laden vector illustrations and
    information graphics.
   </para>
   <para>
    <literal>DIA</literal> files are automatically compressed when saving, thus
    they are often quite small.
   </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="sec.daps.user.imgs.usage.eps">
   <title><literal>EPS</literal></title>
   <important>
    <title>Using EPS files is not recommended</title>
    <para>
     <literal>EPS</literal> support in DAPS is experimental and currently only
     supported in combination with the XEP formatter. Even then, it might lead
     to longer document creation times.
    </para>
   </important>
   <para>
    The <emphasis>Encapsulated Postscript</emphasis> format is a general purpose
    vector image format. As a Postscript-based format, it is similar to
    <literal>PDF</literal>. There is currently no Linux software that creates
    <literal>EPS</literal> files natively, although a number of applications can
    export into it. <literal>EPS</literal> might occasionally serve as an
    exchange format with contributors that use Adobe* graphics software.
   </para>
   <para>
    Where feasible, it is recommended that you use <literal>SVG</literal> files
    instead of <literal>EPS</literal> files.
   </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="sec.daps.user.imgs.usage.fig">
   <title><literal>FIG</literal></title>
   <para>
    <literal>FIG</literal> is a vector image format that can be created with the
    software Xfig. While you should create new illustrations as
    <literal>SVG</literal> files and new diagrams as <literal>DIA</literal>, the
    support for <literal>FIG</literal> can help when working with legacy images.
   </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="sec.daps.user.imgs.usage.pdf">
   <title><literal>PDF</literal></title>
   <important>
    <title>Using PDF files is not recommended</title>
    <para>
     <literal>PDF</literal> support in DAPS is experimental and currently only
     supported in combination with the XEP formatter. Even then, it might lead
     to longer document creation times.
    </para>
   </important>
   <para>
    The <emphasis>Portable Document File</emphasis> format is a general purpose,
    page-based fixed-layout document format. <literal>PDF</literal> is a
    Postscript-based format. There is a large number of Linux software that can
    export <literal>PDF</literal> files natively. <literal>PDF</literal> files
    can also be used as an exchange format with contributors that are unable to
    export to <literal>SVG</literal>.
   </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="sec.daps.user.imgs.usage.png">
   <title><literal>PNG</literal></title>
   <para>
    The <emphasis>Portable Network Graphics</emphasis> format can be used whenever
    you wish to use a raster, that is, point-based image. A good example for when
    to use <literal>PNG</literal> are screenshots and photographs.
   </para>
   <para>
    <literal>PNG</literal> files can be created with a number of applications,
    among them is the GIMP graphics editor.
   </para>
   <tip>
    <title>Use <command>daps optipng</command> to make PNG files smaller</title>
    <para>You can decrease the file size of PNG images without altering their
     look. This is achieved by removing unused colors and alpha channels.
    </para>
    <para>
     To run <command>optipng</command> over an entire book's PNG images, use
     <command>daps -d DC-your-dc-file optipng</command>.
    </para>
   </tip>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="sec.daps.user.imgs.usage.svg">
   <title><literal>SVG</literal></title>
   <para>
    The <emphasis>Scalable Vector Graphics</emphasis> format is a general purpose,
    vector image format. <literal>SVG</literal> is an XML format which can be
    displayed in most browsers and edited in many graphics programs.
   </para>
   <para>
    Under Linux, Mac, and Windows, a good open-source <literal>SVG</literal>
    editor is Inkscape. You can also create <literal>SVG</literal> files from
    many Adobe* products, for instance, from Illustrator*. SVG is the preferred
    vector image format for &daps;.
   </para>
   <tip>
    <title>Check your images in Inkscape</title>
    <para>
     Internally, whenever DAPS needs to convert SVG images to raster images, as
     it does for HTML output files, it uses Inkscape. Therefore, it is a good idea
     to check whether your images render appropriately in Inkscape before
     including them.
    </para>
   </tip>
  </sect2>
 </sect1>
 
</chapter>
